The closest you'll ever want to come to nuclear war.
Threads is a war, drama, science fiction film directed by Mick Jackson.
Documentary style account of a nuclear holocaust and its effect on the working class city of
Sheffield, England; and the eventual long run effects of nuclear war on civilization.
Ruth Beckett, played by Karen Meagher.
Jimmy Kemp, played by Reece Dinsdale.
Mr. Kemp, played by David Brierly.
Mrs. Kemp, played by Rita May.
Michael Kemp, played by Nicholas Lane.
Alison Kemp, played by Jane Hazlegrove.
Threads is a 1984 apocalyptic anti-war drama television film directed
and produced by Mick Jackson and written by Barry Hines.
A dramatic account of the potential medical, economic, social, and environmental consequences of a nuclear war in Britain, it follows two families in Sheffield as
a confrontation between the United States and the Soviet Union erupts into war and a general nuclear exchange between NATO and the Warsaw Pact.
An international co-production between the BBC, Nine Network, and Western-World Television Inc.,
the film was shot on a budget of £400,000 (equivalent to £1,290,611 in 2023).
It was the first of its kind to depict a nuclear winter and has been cited as the film "which comes closest to representing the full
horror of nuclear war and its aftermath, as well as the catastrophic impact that the event would have on human culture".
It has been compared to The War Game (1966) and The Day After (1983).
It was nominated for seven BAFTA Awards in 1985 and won for Best Single
Drama, Best Design, Best Film Cameraman, and Best Film Editor.
The film explores themes of great britain, northern
england, despair, yorkshire, nuclear holocaust.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.